Bharti Patel

UX Designer with background in Visual & Advertising

CONTACT

- **(**510) 221-8063
- bhartip0703@gmail.com
- Fremont, CA
- in linkedin.com/in/bharti7
- bhartiux.github.io

TOOLS

Adobe Creative Suite Sketch 3 InVision Axure MS Office Oracle Webcenter Axure RP 8

SKILLS

User research
User personas
Data synthesis
Rapid prototype
Information architecture
Usability testing
Wireframes
Visual design

EDUCATION

General Assembly

San Francisco, CA
User Experience Design
Immersive program crafted
by top practitioners in the field
-10 weeks Full time
Commercial Arts
Nirmala Niketan, India

CERTIFICATION

Academy X - Web Design Santa Clara, CA Learn IT - Computer Graphics San Mateo, CA

PROFILE

I'm a Designer with a passion for creativity. I believe that simplicity is the ultimate sophistication – that less is more. I have an extensive background in graphic design, web design, and advertising. I bring my experience, passion, and professionalism to any creative task.

EXPERIENCE

UX Designer - Michaels, TX Mar 2020 - July 2020

- Working with the E-comm team for Michaels.com and native app on improving user experience.
- Produced mockups and prototypes while iterating with engineering and product management to meet feature requirements for the existing product.
- Collaborating with Engineering team and PMs from conception to early implementation.

UX / UI Designer - SJSU, San Jose, CA Aug 2019 - Sep 2019

- Worked with the team as UX/Visual/UI designer for creating a new advance analytics platform.
- Worked on landing page and other pages designs to make it more simpler and user-friendly from complex and abstract material following SJSU brand guidelines.
- Produced mockups and prototypes while iterating with engineering and product management to meet feature requirements for the existing product.

UX / UI Designer - Cisco Systems, San Jose, CA Jul 2018 - Oct 2018

- Worked with the team as UX/UI designer for the web application, determining best UX solutions based on customer feedback & business goals. Identifying challenges and adapting as needed based on the context of the solution and customer.
- Created pixel-perfect mocks to communicate user flows and interaction and Visual designs. Delivered redline specs for development following Cisco brand guidelines.
- Collaborated with PMs, developers & engineers from conception to early implementation establishing timelines and consensus from all parties around product flow.

UX/UI Designer - 12 Digit Marketing, Redwood City, CA Jun 2017 - Oct 2017

- Worked with a team to improve UI and providing the right solution to the interface and, delivering pixel perfect mockups for development.
- Producing mockups and prototypes while iterating with engineering and product management to meet feature requirements for the existing product.
- Worked with Client Service Manager/Marketing with visual designs for Retail/Brand creative campaigns delivering responsive designs.

UX Designer & Visual Designer - Cisco Systems, San Jose, CA Jan 2017 - May 2017

- Worked as one of the UX designer & Visual Designer for Cisco VTS (Virtual Topology Systems) product.
- Worked on design to be simpler and user-friendly from complex and abstract material.
- Collaborated with service provider customers like Version and Turk Cell.
- Worked on the Visuals for VTS poster using the personas, for marketing the product., using brand guidelines.
- Produced mockups and prototypes while iterating with engineering and
- Product management to meet feature requirements for the existing product.

*** Was preparing for her UX design course during this period Jan 2016 - Mar 2016 ***

Bharti Patel

UX Designer with background in Visual & Advertising

CONTACT

- **(**510) 221-8063
- bhartip0703@gmail.com
- Fremont, CA
- in linkedin.com/in/bharti7
- bhartiux.github.io

TOOLS

Adobe Creative Suite Sketch 3 InVision Axure MS Office Oracle Webcenter Axure RP 8

SKILLS

User research
User personas
Data synthesis
Rapid prototype
Information architecture
Usability testing
Wireframes
Visual design

EDUCATION

General Assembly

San Francisco, CA
User Experience Design
Immersive program crafted
by top practitioners in the field
-10 weeks Full time
Commercial Arts

Nirmala Niketan, India

CERTIFICATION

Academy X - Web Design Santa Clara, CA Learn IT - Computer Graphics San Mateo, CA

EXPERIENCE

UX Designer - San Francisco Bicycle Coalition (SFBC) March 2016 - April 2016 (as part of General Assembly)

- 2-weeks project to design an mobile app that allows SFBC members to communicate and share with each other.
- User interviews, survey, competitive & comparative analysis, user flow, site maps,
- concept model, and wireframes. Usability testing drove the design of the prototype.

UX Designer - Progress Hardware - Ecommerce website March 2016 (as part of General Assembly)

- 2-weeks project to design an ecommerce website that helps to find right tool for loyal customers who don't like to go to stores, through detailed reviews, update inventory & same day shipping option.
- Used stakeholder interviews, competitive and comparative analysis, card sorting, and usability testing to inform design of global navigation as well as search and check out flows.

Web / Visual Designer - Ross Stores Inc. Dublin, CA Oct 2013 - Dec 2015

- Researched & redesigned intranet portal using Adobe Creative suite & Oracle Webcenter.
- Created meaningful and compelling designs to help users become more productive and frequently visit the portal.
- Worked on design to be simpler and user friendly from complex and abstract material.
- Collaborated extensively across department & with various stakeholders.

Freelance Projects

Web Designer - Drishticon, Fremont, CA Dec 2014 - Mar 2015

- Worked with owner & developers to improve the UI & Visuals of their current website.
- Recreated the current logo & the banners using Adobe Illustrator & Photoshop.

Graphic/ Web Designer - Infinilytics Inc, Santa Clara, CA May 2013 - Jul 2013

- Designed marketing and promotional materials across email, mobile, web, print, and social media.
- Created branding materials logo creation and reconstruction.
- Assisted others with layout and design worked with the marketing department to improve the final product.

Project Manager - United Way SML, Fremont, CA Mar 2009 - May 2009

- Worked as a project manager for redesigning the website for United Way Sonoma Mendocino Lake.
- Responsible for total needs of the client including management of technical and creative resource to deliver complete corporate- quality branding and web solutions.

Web Designer - Ondemandtek, Fremont, CA Jan 2009 - Mar 2009

- Worked with various design tools including Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Illustrator, and Flash to implement web designs and functionality
- Created Logo using Adobe illustrator.